Hello Hello friends, welcome to my
channel in college today we will tell you about the types of balances
in insurance. We are quite confused about Vikram
insurance.
Who is the first party, who is the second party,
who is the third party, so
friends, the first party is like we
insured our car and our car meets with an
accident with another car, so what happens to us, what happens to
us,
first party insurance,
what happens to the second party office, this insurance
company which
gives you insurance, like you have HDFC,
ICICI, New India Insurance, what will happen to all these, what happens to
you, what happens to the third party among the second parties,
if Viking and
Advik loan are the owners of another vehicle, let's
assume that when your car
collides with another vehicle, there is a collision, then
whatever parts are damaged in the other vehicle,
whatever losses occur,
your insurance company
provides it, if there is any damage to your vehicle, if there is
any loss, then
the company does not provide you with it,
you do not get any benefit from it, so other
vehicle  We
also call it liability only insurance
against the owner. What happens in depression?
During depression, there are some advanced features
which we take with a comprehensive policy, that is, if
you take Jhajjar Road, then we get a
hundred percent claim in it. In some cases,
friends, we get a 50% claim,
like if the balance is settled, or if the settlement is settled, then in all these cases,
we get a 50% claim.
We get 36, 30 percent claim on fiberglass companies
and we do
not get any claim on glass components. This is a flight,
friends, which we
take with a comprehensive policy. It is not added with third party.
What happens in party insurance,
friends, when our car
collides with another car, an
accident happens, then
whatever parts of the car get damaged in the other car,
whatever increases, now our
insurance company gives it to us.
We do not get any claim on our car.
We call third party insurance as Lal
Ki Police. Friends, this
liability is called Suraj because
When your car collides with another car,
your car does
not get any claim. Whatever damage is done to your car
or any injury occurs, then
you will have to bear the entire cost of your car yourself,
but the
other party which collided with your car
gets the entire money. If there is any accident,
this is a date, whose property gets
damaged due to this, third party verification
Jyoti, like someone's house is hit by your car, or any
direct collision occurs with your car,
your insurance company will provide all the things to you and other third parties. The
maximum cover limit which varies in this is
1 lakh on Nikhil and the
company gives you Rs. 7.5 lakh cover, but if
you keep in mind that if you are
driving the car after typing OK, then you will
not get any claim. You have to follow the terms and conditions
very carefully.
See friends, if there is an injury or damage, then in
this way the company on this is unlimited, there is a
claim on this, there are placements, it is unlimited,
it is seen that  If there is an injury, then for how many
days will the person who has an
accident and for how many days will he not go to office,
how much income did he earn,
how much liability does he have at home, how many people were
dependent on him, the company looks at all these things and
then gives him a game, there is no
limit on injury in this,
but the limit of the car is seven
lakhs and the limit in searching for an option is the
highest, if we had taken
insurance custom then they would
not have issued us a challan, only this much damage is caused, when
you buy a policy then
we should carefully check the terms and conditions of that company,
what are its special conditions,
in a comprehensive policy friends, the
first party is the one with which the car has an
accident and the second car has an
accident, then
where is the claim of both the vehicles, it is
available from Supaul, on
which claim is not available in it,
like we have installed an extra message, there
is an engine, even if the engine goes into water then
we do not get a claim on it, for this
we have to take a separate don't feature,
I am definitely a defense politician  Life has
advanced features, those which we take
come under comprehensive policy,
what happens in a new news for personal injury for bike insurance, if there is a personal injury
then there is no cover in it,
for that we have to do Gabbar bike at the back, at
what time should I come after testing,
we do not have to pay any amount,
if there is any injury in car insurance then in
comprehensive policy the
company pays the entire amount, it is
covered by compression for your vehicle,
along with that the
other vehicle which is with you is also covered completely by low pressure,
friends we should keep this thing in mind, these people
say that when there is a car
accident then only we
get insurance in the policy from the company phone, no
friends natural disasters like earthquake might have happened, the car might have caught
fire, the car might have
collided with an animal,
some spider-man might have happened in the car or there might be a
fire on the train due to any natural disaster,
mother should be increased, there might be an earthquake which  Whatever
losses we incur due to natural calamities,
all of them are covered in comprehensive insurance. Let me
explain, friends, there is one
more thing, if there is accident cover, then the
government gives 2 lakh rupees in personal accident as well, but by the way, there is
no comprehensive personal accident cover in bike insurance, for this
we have to take separate claim feature, which
features are better for you friends, which
policy is good for you, as per our understanding,
which comprehensive is the best
because under section 98th you will have to get insurance
otherwise your challan will be
deducted, so according to us, low
pressure is probably better, if you
wipe the car with a cloth, then all the things are
covered in it, whereas in two wheelers, there is
no personal accident cover in bikes, for that
we have to take separate claim
feature, a
comprehensive insurance, friends, there is a
fast claim process in cars, in cars, in bikes, there is a
compensation cover in all, the
first claim process is done quickly
and in third party insurance, there is a
slow claim process.
From a comprehensive point of view, what happens is
that the claim process is very fast
because the insurance company from which
we have taken insurance processes the
equivalent claim and it is
in its hands, but
what happens in the third party, the next process in the third party is
slow
because the one who handles this process is the
Insurance City, that is, the
Motor Accident Claims Tribunal,
what happens in this, friends, it takes a lot of time to
take a third party claim,
friends, according to us, it is
better to take comprehensive insurance as per the third
party because
if we talk about comprehensive insurance for a car, then if the car
is not there then it is the best and if it becomes
old then it has
some advanced features and due to this
we have to pay a higher premium, still reduce it
from the people who are more according to the third party,
son wrap, friends, if you
like this video of ours then please like,
share and subscribe.